<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Grande Hot Chocolate]]></title>
  <link href="http://ayau.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ayau.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-24T01:32:16-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ayau.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alex]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
    <link href="http://ayau.github.com/blog/2013/03/21/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-21T16:07:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ayau.github.com/blog/2013/03/21/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of my new year&#8217;s resolution this year is to start a blog.</p>

<p>I have been meant to do that for a while now, but was struggling between choosing different platforms. I was looking between <a href="www.tumblr.com">tumblr</a>, <a href="www.wordpress.com">wordpress</a> and a self hosted, Jerkyll blog. From what I have heard, tumblr is more for pictures and wordpress is too complicated and not very flexible (at least if you want to use it for free). Both have great communities already established and will probably be easier for promoting blog content.</p>

<p>What I really wanted to do was to write down the random thoughts and theories that I have during the day (mostly during lunch with my roommate David) and share some experiences of computer science, entrepreneurship or just life in general. For those reasons, Jerkyll seems like a very attractive option - once it is set up. Setting up seems like a bitch though. Then I found <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Octopress is a framework designed by <a href="http://brandonmathis.com/">Brandon Mathis</a> for Jerkyll with a lot of third party plugins. I used it with <a href="http://pages.github.com/">Github Pages</a>, which is a free hosting service provided by Github (very nice of them to), and the <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/setup/">tutorial</a> on Octopress is easy enough to follow. As a programmer, I already have git and ruby installed, which sped up the process a lot. It took about 5 minutes before I was able to deploy an empty blog to <a href="http://grandehotchocolate.com">grandehotchocolate.com</a>.</p>

<h1>Design</h1>

<p>I was a little annoyed at the default design (it wasn&#8217;t that bad, I just didn&#8217;t really like it). I searched for octopress themes and found a <a href="https://github.com/imathis/octopress/wiki/3rd-Party-Octopress-Themes">list of 3rd party themes</a>. I chose <a href="https://github.com/shashankmehta/greyshade">Greyshade</a> which is developed by <a href="http://shashankmehta.in/archive/2012/greyshade.html">Shashank Mehta</a>.</p>

<p>I really like the simple and responsive design in Greyshade. As I was looking through the code in the theme, I started making minor adjustments to see which elements are affected by certain css selectors, which turned into an uncontrollable 4 hour nonstop design session. I drew inspirations from <a href="http://cyrilmottier.com/">Cyril Mottier&#8217;s blog</a> since I really enjoy the color scheme and layout he chose (he also has great content on mobile development). The avatar is a similar style to the ones used on <a href="https://svbtle.com/">Svbtle</a> and I made a custom one that looks like the Grande Hot Chocolate you would get at Starbucks (Hope you can tell from the image!)</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll probably end up redesigning the site later when I have time but it looks good enough for now.</p>

<hr />

<p>The purpose of this post is mostly for me to test out blogging with Octopress. Keep an eye out for upcoming posts that may actually seem interesting :D</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll end with some cool tools I recently found.</p>

<h1>Cool tools for blogging</h1>

<p><a href="http://tmpvar.com/markdown.html">Markdown live preview</a> - since Jerkyll processes blog posts with markdown, it may be useful to see a live preview as you are writing</p>

<p><a href="http://robdodson.me/blog/2012/06/23/sublime-text-2-tips-and-shortcuts/">Sublime text shortcuts</a> - for people who blog with sublime text</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
